{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The internal RAM memory of the 8051 is:", "opta": "32 bytes", "optb": "64 bytes", "optc": "128 bytes", "optd": "256 bytes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This program code will be executed continuously:  STAT: MOV A, #01H \u00a0JNZ STAT", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8051 has ________ 16-bit counter/timers.", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The address space of the 8051 is divided into four distinct areas: internal data, external data, internal code, and external code.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Data transfer from I/O to external data memory can only be done with the MOVX command.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8051 can handle ________ interrupt sources.", "opta": "3", "optb": "4", "optc": "5", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "There are five interrupt sources for the 8051, which means that they can recognize 5 different events that can interrupt regular program execution. Each interrupt can be enabled or disabled by setting bits of the IE register. Likewise, the whole interrupt system can be disabled by clearing the EA bit of the same register."}, {"question": "The special function registers are maintained in the next 128 locations after the general-purpose data storage and stack.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This statement will set the address of the bit to 1 (8051 Micro-controller):  SETB 01H", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "MOV A, @ R1 will:", "opta": "copy R1 to the accumulator", "optb": "copy the accumulator to R1", "optc": "copy the contents of memory whose address is in R1 to the accumulator", "optd": "copy the accumulator to the contents of memory whose address is in R1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A label is used to name a single line of code.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following program will receive data from port 1, determine whether bit 2 is high, and then send the number FFH to port 3:  READ: MOV A,P1 ANL A,#2H CJNE A,#02H,READ MOV P3,#FFH", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Device pins XTAL1 and XTAL2 for the 8051 are used for connections to an external oscillator or crystal.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the 8051 is reset and the  line is HIGH, the program counter points to the first program instruction in the:", "opta": "internal code memory", "optb": "external code memory", "optc": "internal data memory", "optd": "external data memory", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An alternate function of port pin P3.4 in the 8051 is:", "opta": "Timer 0", "optb": "Timer 1", "optc": "interrupt 0", "optd": "interrupt 1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Both registers TL0 and TL1 are needed to start Timer 0.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The I/O ports that are used as address and data for external memory are:", "opta": "ports 1 and 2", "optb": "ports 1 and 3", "optc": "ports 0 and 2", "optd": "ports 0 and 3", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The last 96 locations in the internal data memory are reserved for general-purpose data storage and stack.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microcontrollers often have:", "opta": "CPUs", "optb": "RAM", "optc": "ROM", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8051 has ________ parallel I/O ports.", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total external data memory that can be interfaced to the 8051 is:", "opta": "32K", "optb": "64K", "optc": "128K", "optd": "256K", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following instructions will load the value 35H into the high byte of timer 0?", "opta": "MOV TH0, #35H", "optb": "MOV TH0, 35H", "optc": "MOV T0, #35H", "optd": "MOV T0, 35H", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bit-addressable memory locations are:", "opta": "10H through 1FH", "optb": "20H through 2FH", "optc": "30H through 3FH", "optd": "40H through 4FH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 8-bit address bus allows access to an address range of:", "opta": "0000 to FFFFH", "optb": "000 to FFFH", "optc": "00 to FFH", "optd": "0 to FH", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The contents of the accumulator after this operation  MOV A,#0BH ANL A,#2CH will be", "opta": "11010111", "optb": "11011010", "optc": "00001000", "optd": "00101000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The start-conversion on the ADC0804 is done by using the:", "opta": "", "optb": "CS line", "optc": "INTR line", "optd": "V ref/2 line", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This program code will be executed once:  STAT: MOV A, #01H \u00a0JNZ STAT", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following instructions will move the contents of register 3 to the accumulator?", "opta": "MOV 3R, A", "optb": "MOV R3, A", "optc": "MOV A, R3", "optd": "MOV A, 3R", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements will add the accumulator and register 3?", "opta": "ADD @R3, @A", "optb": "ADD @A, R3", "optc": "ADD R3, A", "optd": "ADD A, R3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Data transfer from I/O to external data memory can only be done with the MOV command.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will move the number 27H into the accumulator?", "opta": "MOV A, P27", "optb": "MOV A, #27H", "optc": "MOV A, 27H", "optd": "MOV A, @27", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "This program code will read data from port 0 and write it to port 2, and it will stop looping when bit 3 of port 2 is set:  STAT: MOV A, PO \u00a0MOV P2,A \u00a0JNB P2.3, STAT", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will move the value at port 3 to register 2?", "opta": "MOV P2, R3", "optb": "MOV R3, P2", "optc": "MOV 3P, R2", "optd": "MOV R2, P3", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of data registers is:", "opta": "8", "optb": "16", "optc": "32", "optd": "64", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the 8051 is reset and the EA line is LOW, the program counter points to the first program instruction in the:", "opta": "internal code memory", "optb": "external code memory", "optc": "internal data memory", "optd": "external data memory", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The designs of a centigrade thermometer and a PWM speed-control circuit can be implemented by the 8051.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between the 8031 and the 8051?", "opta": "The 8031 has no interrupts.", "optb": "The 8031 is ROM-less.", "optc": "The 8051 is ROM-less.", "optd": "The 8051 has 64 bytes more memory.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The I/O port that does not have a dual-purpose role is:", "opta": "port 0", "optb": "port 1", "optc": "port 2", "optd": "port 3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To interface external EPROM memory for applications, it is necessary to demultiplex the address/data lines of the 8051.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following command will copy the accumulator to the location whose address is 23H: MOV 23H,A", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The special function registers can be referred to by their hex addresses or by their register names.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The contents of the accumulator after this operation  MOV A,#2BH ORL A,00H will be:", "opta": "1B H", "optb": "2B H", "optc": "3B H", "optd": "4B H", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following program will cause the 8051 to be stuck in a loop:  LOOP: MOV A, #00H \u00a0JNZ LOOP", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will copy the contents of RAM whose address is in register 0 to port 1?", "opta": "MOV @ P1, R0", "optb": "MOV @ R0, P1", "optc": "MOV P1, @ R0", "optd": "MOV P1, R0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The statement LCALL READ passes control to the line labelled READ.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will copy the contents of location 4H to the accumulator?", "opta": "MOV A, 04H", "optb": "MOV A, L4", "optc": "MOV L4, A", "optd": "MOV 04H, A", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The microcontroller is useful in systems that have nonvariable programs for dedicated applications.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total amount of external code memory that can be interfaced to the 8051 is:", "opta": "32K", "optb": "64K", "optc": "128K", "optd": "256K", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ADC0804 has ________ resolution.", "opta": "4-bit", "optb": "8-bit", "optc": "16-bit", "optd": "32-bit", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A HIGH on which pin resets the 8051 microcontroller?", "opta": "RESET", "optb": "RST", "optc": "PSEN", "optd": "RSET", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An alternate function of port pin P3.1 in the 8051 is:", "opta": "serial port input", "optb": "serial port output", "optc": "memory write strobe", "optd": "memory read strobe", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following instructions will move the contents of the accumulator to register 6?", "opta": "MOV 6R, A", "optb": "MOV R6, A", "optc": "MOV A, 6R", "optd": "MOV A, R6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The following command will rotate the 8 bits of the accumulator one position to the left:  RL A", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An alternate function of port pin P3.0 (RXD) in the 8051 is:", "opta": "serial port input", "optb": "serial port output", "optc": "memory write strobe", "optd": "memory read strobe", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}